<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Welcome to Helen&#39;s journal!</title>
    <link href="/2022/10/07/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2022/10/07/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey friend!<br>This blog is created to pin the updates of my study&#x2F;work in journalism, reading, photographing, meeting with people etc.</p><span id="more"></span><p>To clarify the name of this page, STEP-HOP is a dance step consisting of a forward step followed by a hop on the same foot. In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=no3BbjUp4Dg">Quickstep</a> of ballroom dancing, this step is used to turn around and move towards a new direction. This word gives a sense of stepping to the next stage of path, and this is exactly my expectation for career, life and the world.</p><p>Let’s <strong>step hop</strong>! Continue reading to know about meeeee!</p><h3 id="Study-journalism-amp-communication-in-PKU-then-THU"><a href="#Study-journalism-amp-communication-in-PKU-then-THU" class="headerlink" title="Study journalism &amp; communication in PKU then THU"></a>Study journalism &amp; communication in PKU then THU</h3><h3 id="Excited-with-data-but-still-a-beginner"><a href="#Excited-with-data-but-still-a-beginner" class="headerlink" title="Excited with data but still a beginner"></a>Excited with data but still a beginner</h3><p>Leyi’s feeds herself with creative stories and visual designs from branding advertising cases to data essays. Crafting stories with a combination of media forms and cutting-edge technology is her emphasis for graduate school learning.</p><h3 id="Puzzle-games-amp-ballroom-dancing-in-leisure"><a href="#Puzzle-games-amp-ballroom-dancing-in-leisure" class="headerlink" title="Puzzle games &amp; ballroom dancing in leisure"></a>Puzzle games &amp; ballroom dancing in leisure</h3><p>Leyi watches drama series in her leisure time. Sherlock Holmes and Fleabag are her favorite. This year she has been hooked on real-time role-playing games and conducted a little study based on observations and experiences. Besides these she spent most of her time in ballroom dancing, which “invigorates the body and liberates the brain from unlimited thinking,” as she said. </p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>About me</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
