<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Digital Hamster</title>
    <link href="/2022/10/10/Digital-Hamster/"/>
    <url>/2022/10/10/Digital-Hamster/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>数据仓鼠：大量囤积数字内容相信未来终有一天会使用……</p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="经验帖"><a href="#经验帖" class="headerlink" title="经验帖"></a>经验帖</h2><p><a href="https://blog.csdn.net/YYIverson?type=blog">CSDN博主1</a><br>数据分析学习经验</p><h2 id="Data-source"><a href="#Data-source" class="headerlink" title="Data source"></a>Data source</h2><p>公安部户政管理研究中心提供了<a href="https://www.mps.gov.cn/n2254314/n6409334/c8349265/content.html">全国姓名报告</a>,更新至2021年。<br><a href="https://www.mps.gov.cn/">公安部</a>官网。政府信息公开入口有点卡。<br><a href="https://www.cnopendata.com/data/m/recent/recruitment.html">CnOpenData</a><br><a href="https://blog.csdn.net/qq_36744449/article/details/124460466">政府开放数据</a></p><h2 id="教程帖"><a href="#教程帖" class="headerlink" title="教程帖"></a>教程帖</h2><p><a href="http://blog.apps.npr.org/2014/05/09/responsive-data-tables.html">NPR分享</a>的responsive table代码<br><a href="https://flowingdata.com/books/">FlowingData推荐书单</a>，包含商务数据图表、数据新闻的入门书籍。</p><h2 id="Visualisation"><a href="#Visualisation" class="headerlink" title="Visualisation"></a>Visualisation</h2><p><a href="https://datajournalism.com/discuss">datajournalism</a><br><a href="https://create.piktochart.com/output/38783444-blockchain-where-s-the-way-out-after-the-boom">PICTOCHART</a>a tool to generate slide-like visuals</p><p><a href="https://www.it610.com/article/1404129359492599808.htm">可视化图表的blog文章</a></p><h3 id="Index-中文数据新闻作品"><a href="#Index-中文数据新闻作品" class="headerlink" title="Index-中文数据新闻作品"></a>Index-中文数据新闻作品</h3><p><a href="https://www.imokey.cn/sicnu/index.html">中国地铁五十年</a> 丰富的数据来源，主要采用charts，数据可视化不统一，叙事弱<br><a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/BUo6WZs3u44gy9bvPoRAYQ">零糖食品与控糖</a> 数据以文本为主，豆瓣小组+京东评论，词频研究<br><a href="">数据火锅公众号搜索关键词案例</a><br>mooc<br><a href="https://www.icourse163.org/course/JHC-1205898819?from=searchPage&outVendor=zw_mooc_pcssjg_">游戏可视化编程</a><br>data journalism playbook<br>story telling with data<br>写作脑科学<br>story board</p><h2 id="工具"><a href="#工具" class="headerlink" title="工具"></a>工具</h2><p><a href="https://www.wyzowl.com/">Animation-making platform(with digital marketing data)</a></p><h2 id="Analytics"><a href="#Analytics" class="headerlink" title="Analytics"></a>Analytics</h2>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Tech-study</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Greeting Thao from Tsinghua GBJ</title>
    <link href="/2022/10/09/QA-GBJ/"/>
    <url>/2022/10/09/QA-GBJ/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>5 questions to know about Thao Nguyen, a new student of Tsinghua Global Business Journalism program from Vietnam.</p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="Carrer-in-Hochiminh"><a href="#Carrer-in-Hochiminh" class="headerlink" title="Carrer in Hochiminh"></a>Carrer in Hochiminh</h2><p class="note note-primary">Q1: Before you come to Tsinghua GBJ program, where were you?</p><p><strong>Thao:</strong> I worked for CHANNEL as a marketing manager the year before. Before that I worked for Unilever and then moved to the luxury brand. I was based in Hochiminh city in Vietnam, while I completed my undergraduate school in London, UK.</p><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/Thao3.jpg"></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/Thao4.jpg"></div></div><div class="group-image-row"></div></div><h2 id="Why-Tsinghua-GBJ"><a href="#Why-Tsinghua-GBJ" class="headerlink" title="Why Tsinghua GBJ"></a>Why Tsinghua GBJ</h2><p class="note note-primary">Q2: How did you made the decision to come to Tsinghua?</p><p><strong>Thao:</strong> I learned about the syllabus, courses, and culture, and found the university is well-suited for my goal. There is a psychological center that I would like to explore more. The humanity of this university and the activeness of Tsinghua students on social media attracted me.<br>Then I found GBJ program. There are courses focusing on mass media communication in modern China. For me, China is a nation with a diversified culture which definitely worth exploring. </p><h2 id="Refresh-to-re-start"><a href="#Refresh-to-re-start" class="headerlink" title="Refresh to re-start"></a>Refresh to re-start</h2><p class="note note-primary">Q3: What does going back to campus means to you, given that you've had years of working experiences?</p><p><strong>Thao:</strong> My attempt to come to Tsinghua is to refresh my career life. I’m not scoring high. Before looking at programs in Tsinghua, I was in the application process for MBA of Singapore, when I did a self-reflection and questioned whether MBA was what I wanted. </p><iframe frameborder="no" border="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" width=330 height=86 src="//music.163.com/outchain/player?type=3&id=2512113752&auto=0&height=66"></iframe><p>My new plan for career is to work for my own start-up, which would be a coffee chain store. My grandparents own a coffee farm in Vietnam, and I myself have rich experiences and knowledge in producing and recognizing coffee. In my plan, profits will be donated to charities that help with health problems in the young generation.</p><img src="/2022/10/09/QA-GBJ/Thao6.jpg" class="" title="Thao said goobye to CHANNEL and come to Tsinghua"><h2 id="Journalism-Not-a-must"><a href="#Journalism-Not-a-must" class="headerlink" title="Journalism? Not a must"></a>Journalism? Not a must</h2><p class="note note-primary">Q4: What do you think about journalism?</p><p><strong>Thao:</strong> I was thinking of choosing a master’s program in communication, but I never thought about taking journalism as a career. Instead, I leverage journalism as means to support my campaign in the future. This will better my skill in writing, and help me maintain partnership for my brand.</p><h2 id="Interest-driven-by-Covid…"><a href="#Interest-driven-by-Covid…" class="headerlink" title="Interest driven by Covid…"></a>Interest driven by Covid…</h2><p class="note note-primary">Q5: Why you concerns about mental health so much?</p><p><strong>Thao:</strong> I have friends doing business in hotels and restaurants who faced great pressure under Covid. Though they’re restarting the business now, there was a very hard time for them, when they even got into depression. I think mental health is not only the top priority but also a fashion.</p><div align=center><img src="/img/Thao2.jpg" height="75%" width="75%"></div><br>Thao is coming back to Tsinghua in the comming week. Also professors teaching in the GBJ program are planning to return to Beijing after two years of working remotely. ]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Talker</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Welcome to Helen&#39;s journal!</title>
    <link href="/2022/10/07/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2022/10/07/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey friend! </p><p>This blog is created to pin the updates of my study&#x2F;work in journalism, reading, photographing, meeting with people etc.</p><span id="more"></span><p>To clarify the name of this page, STEP-HOP is a dance step consisting of a forward step followed by a hop on the same foot. In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=no3BbjUp4Dg">Quickstep</a> of ballroom dancing, this step is used to turn around and move towards a new direction. This word gives a sense of stepping to the next stage of path, and this is exactly my expectation for career, life and the world.</p><p>Let’s <strong>step hop</strong>! Continue reading to know about meeeee!</p><h3 id="Study-journalism-amp-communication-in-PKU-then-THU"><a href="#Study-journalism-amp-communication-in-PKU-then-THU" class="headerlink" title="Study journalism &amp; communication in PKU then THU"></a>Study journalism &amp; communication in PKU then THU</h3><p>I’m studying for my double-degree master’s program of Journalism and Data Science at Tsinghua University. I graduated from Peking University with a bachelor’s degree in advertising in 2022, where I joined PKU Youth, a school media community, and worked as the chief editor for a year. At PKU Youth I interviewed people, operated the WeChat account, conducted investigations and wrote features. </p><p>Experiences as a student journalist was so amazing! I felt invigorated when listening to stories, taking them down and waiting for the story to get released. It’s also motivating to think of using media literacy to inlfuence people’s perception and behavior and change a little bit of the world.</p><h3 id="Excited-with-data-but-still-a-beginner"><a href="#Excited-with-data-but-still-a-beginner" class="headerlink" title="Excited with data but still a beginner"></a>Excited with data but still a beginner</h3><p>During the past summer holiday of 2022, I found great pleasure in exploring information visualization designs from branding advertising cases to data essays. Crafting stories with a combination of media forms and cutting-edge technology becomes my emphasis for graduate school learning. </p><h3 id="Puzzle-games-amp-ballroom-dancing-in-leisure"><a href="#Puzzle-games-amp-ballroom-dancing-in-leisure" class="headerlink" title="Puzzle games &amp; ballroom dancing in leisure"></a>Puzzle games &amp; ballroom dancing in leisure</h3><p>I watche drama series in her leisure time. Sherlock Holmes and Fleabag are my favorite! This year I has been hooked on real-time role-playing games and conducted a little study based on observations and experiences. Besides these I spent most of my time in ballroom dancing, which I started learning two years ago. This is me in a standard dancing.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>About me</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
