<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Greeting Thao from Tsinghua GBJ</title>
    <link href="/2022/10/09/QA-GBJ/"/>
    <url>/2022/10/09/QA-GBJ/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>5 questions to know about Thao Nguyen, a new student of Tsinghua Global Business Journalism program from Vietnam.</p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="Carrer-in-Hochiminh"><a href="#Carrer-in-Hochiminh" class="headerlink" title="Carrer in Hochiminh"></a>Carrer in Hochiminh</h2><p class="note note-primary">Q1: Before you come to Tsinghua GBJ program, where were you?</p><p><strong>Thao:</strong> I worked for CHANNEL as a marketing manager the year before. Before that I worked for Unilever and then moved to the luxury brand. I was based in Hochiminh city in Vietnam, while I completed my undergraduate school in London, UK.</p><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/Thao3.jpg"></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/Thao4.jpg"></div></div><div class="group-image-row"></div></div><h2 id="Why-Tsinghua-GBJ"><a href="#Why-Tsinghua-GBJ" class="headerlink" title="Why Tsinghua GBJ"></a>Why Tsinghua GBJ</h2><p class="note note-primary">Q2: How did you made the decision to come to Tsinghua?</p><p><strong>Thao:</strong> I learned about the syllabus, courses, and culture, and found the university is well-suited for my goal. There is a psychological center that I would like to explore more. The humanity of this university and the activeness of Tsinghua students on social media attracted me.<br>Then I found GBJ program. There are courses focusing on mass media communication in modern China. For me, China is a nation with a diversified culture which definitely worth exploring. </p><h2 id="Refresh-to-re-start"><a href="#Refresh-to-re-start" class="headerlink" title="Refresh to re-start"></a>Refresh to re-start</h2><p class="note note-primary">Q3: What does going back to campus means to you, given that you've had years of working experiences?</p><p><strong>Thao:</strong> My attempt to come to Tsinghua is to refresh my career life. I’m not scoring high. Before looking at programs in Tsinghua, I was in the application process for MBA of Singapore, when I did a self-reflection and questioned whether MBA was what I wanted. </p><iframe frameborder="no" border="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" width=330 height=86 src="//music.163.com/outchain/player?type=3&id=2512113752&auto=0&height=66"></iframe><p>My new plan for career is to work for my own start-up, which would be a coffee chain store. My grandparents own a coffee farm in Vietnam, and I myself have rich experiences and knowledge in producing and recognizing coffee. In my plan, profits will be donated to charities that help with health problems in the young generation.</p><img src="/2022/10/09/QA-GBJ/Thao6.jpg" class="" title="Thao said goobye to CHANNEL and come to Tsinghua"><h2 id="Journalism-Not-a-must"><a href="#Journalism-Not-a-must" class="headerlink" title="Journalism? Not a must"></a>Journalism? Not a must</h2><p class="note note-primary">Q4: What do you think about journalism?</p><p><strong>Thao:</strong> I was thinking of choosing a master’s program in communication, but I never thought about taking journalism as a career. Instead, I leverage journalism as means to support my campaign in the future. This will better my skill in writing, and help me maintain partnership for my brand.</p><h2 id="Interest-driven-by-Covid…"><a href="#Interest-driven-by-Covid…" class="headerlink" title="Interest driven by Covid…"></a>Interest driven by Covid…</h2><p class="note note-primary">Q5: Why you concerns about mental health so much?</p><p><strong>Thao:</strong> I have friends doing business in hotels and restaurants who faced great pressure under Covid. Though they’re restarting the business now, there was a very hard time for them, when they even got into depression. I think mental health is not only the top priority but also a fashion.</p><div align=center><img src="/img/Thao2.jpg" height="75%" width="75%"></div><br>Thao is coming back to Tsinghua in the comming week. Also professors teaching in the GBJ program are planning to return to Beijing after two years of working remotely. ]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Talker</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Welcome to Helen&#39;s journal!</title>
    <link href="/2022/10/07/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2022/10/07/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey friend!<br>This blog is created to pin the updates of my study&#x2F;work in journalism, reading, photographing, meeting with people etc.</p><span id="more"></span><p>To clarify the name of this page, STEP-HOP is a dance step consisting of a forward step followed by a hop on the same foot. In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=no3BbjUp4Dg">Quickstep</a> of ballroom dancing, this step is used to turn around and move towards a new direction. This word gives a sense of stepping to the next stage of path, and this is exactly my expectation for career, life and the world.</p><p>Let’s <strong>step hop</strong>! Continue reading to know about meeeee!</p><h3 id="Study-journalism-amp-communication-in-PKU-then-THU"><a href="#Study-journalism-amp-communication-in-PKU-then-THU" class="headerlink" title="Study journalism &amp; communication in PKU then THU"></a>Study journalism &amp; communication in PKU then THU</h3><h3 id="Excited-with-data-but-still-a-beginner"><a href="#Excited-with-data-but-still-a-beginner" class="headerlink" title="Excited with data but still a beginner"></a>Excited with data but still a beginner</h3><p>Leyi’s feeds herself with creative stories and visual designs from branding advertising cases to data essays. Crafting stories with a combination of media forms and cutting-edge technology is her emphasis for graduate school learning.</p><h3 id="Puzzle-games-amp-ballroom-dancing-in-leisure"><a href="#Puzzle-games-amp-ballroom-dancing-in-leisure" class="headerlink" title="Puzzle games &amp; ballroom dancing in leisure"></a>Puzzle games &amp; ballroom dancing in leisure</h3><p>Leyi watches drama series in her leisure time. Sherlock Holmes and Fleabag are her favorite. This year she has been hooked on real-time role-playing games and conducted a little study based on observations and experiences. Besides these she spent most of her time in ballroom dancing, which “invigorates the body and liberates the brain from unlimited thinking,” as she said. </p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>About me</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
